### (757) 374 0095 · emilygmacon@gmail.com San Francisco, CA · www.EmilyMacon.com

## **EMILY MACON**

I am a visual designer who has brought brands to life, built front-end websites, and led teams across design and engineering. Visually, I'm an expert letterer, illustrator, Bezier wrangler, and colorist. Cognitively, I'm a detail-oriented project manager, working fast without sacrificing quality, attention to detail, or losing sight of the broader goal. While I'm proud of my design eye, my most valuable quality is the ability to (successfully) implement any project from conception to completion.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **SENSE**

Senior Visual Designer ♦ San Francisco ♦ April 2019 - Present

- Led all visual design across Product, Marketing, and Sales (eBooks, blog images, digital ads, conference swag, embroidered jackets, one-pagers, sales decks, digital paintings, custom lettering, ad hoc digital and print collateral)
- Revamped and streamlined design team resources and processes
- Spearheaded yet-to-be-released company rebrand positioning Sense as leading staffing automation company, straddling both SF technology startup and traditional staffing customer base

#### **EMI ART & DESIGN LLC**

**Independent Visual Designer** ♦ San Francisco ♦ Feb 2016 - Present Projects ranging from lettering & illustration to web & product design

- Lead designer for Eliqs (contract) responsible for logo design and branding, illustrations, >40 custom can designs, all marketing collateral, and communications with both client and supply side partners
- Logos and branding for several clients including Falling in Love with Leah Lamarr podcast, Meet my Mom with Jenna Carley podcast, Noh Leftovers, Proof of Impact, and many other Bay Area and LA-based startups
- Web design and implementation for Humboldt Legends
- Email templates, product site pages, and pitch deck for Feastly

#### **ICUEMOTION**

**Lead Visual Designer** ♦ San Francisco ♦ May 2016 – Dec 2018 Lead Designer under top robotics engineer Bérénice Mettler, Ph.D.

- Translated complex data and concepts into digestible visualizations across all
  user touches from company branding to the app, website, and beyond
- Developed CueMate's visual language: illustration, animation, brand guidelines
- Designed + coded website for CueMate products and iCueMotion R&D Lab
- Designed app UX/UI; managed team of engineers for implementation
- Managed beta cohort validating technology and testing UX/UI

#### **MARKETBRIDGE**

**Designer**, **Consultant** ♦ San Francisco, Washington DC ♦ July 2013 – Nov 2015 I started at the boutique consulting firm as a Consultant. After clear interest in design, I was promoted to a custom Design role focusing on data visualization.

- Designed training tools for Saks Fifth Avenue associates to pitch SaksFirst credit cards to customers, doubling credit card activation within the first year
- Designed all infographics for Humana marketing campaign that contributed to 3x active user base; managed Humana's 3-person web development team, 13 copy writers, and 4 partners and redesigned the site UX, increasing both article page views and time on page by 20%
- Designed >100 client-facing decks and misc. projects for clients such as Microsoft, PayPal, Cisco, Neiman Marcus, HP, and Dell

#### SKILLS AND TOOLS

- Procreate for illustration & lettering
- Adobe Illustrator for icons and general vector graphic design
- Adobe Photoshop for image editing and simple animation
- Adobe InDesign for books and zines
- Adobe Animate for complex animation
- **Sketch** for web and app design
- Invision for rapid prototyping
- Robofont for typeface development and instances benefiting from more control over Bezier curves. For meticulous type design: Superpolator and MetricsMachine
- Extremely proficient in HTML/CSS and can navigate JS + React; track changes with Git

#### **EDUCATION**

UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA McIntire School of Commerce, College of Arts & Sciences

Double Major: BS Commerce, BA Studio Art GPA: 3.92/4.0, Dean's List all semesters, Graduated with High Distinction

# TYPE@COOPER WEST EXTENDED PROGRAM (COOPER UNION) Type Certification, 2017-18

Created two character complete type families Comprehensive study of type design technique, technology, expression, history & theory

#### **HOBBIES**

- Hand and vector lettering
- Identifying typefaces in the wild
- Illustration and figure drawing
- Large-scale oil paintings
- Making things with Sculpey

#### **AWARDS & RECOGNITION**

Sunsets on the River 2019 competition winner ♦ Provided visuals & test question bank for How Business Works textbook now used in most US colleges ♦ Vance and Betty Lee Stickell Award, chosen as 1 of 15 students recognized nationally based on professors' recommendations and leadership qualities ♦ National Association of Newspaper Editors 1st in Best Illustration, 2nd in Best Political Cartoon ♦ Selected for city grant to have art on building exterior in ORF Arts District